フルプラ
Fool on the Planet
本字幕由 SweetSub 制作　仅做交流学习之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
所以这见鬼的东西竖起来了
So, the damn thing stood up.
烟雾在弥漫
It's getting pretty foggy.
太阳上升到顶空的时候就会散去的
It'll go away once the sun is at its peak.
你用不着来的
It wasn't necessary for you to come, you know.
还是说你害怕我把它扔掉？
Or were you concerned that I would throw it away?
如果它以前的力量还残留哪怕一点点…
If this has even a fraction of the power it used to have...
别想这个了 别担心
Just forget about it. Don't worry.
■
大豆市某处
入国管理局轨道电梯前
喂 冠军
Hey, champ.
你还在为未来而努力训练吗？
Are you training hard for tomorrow?
呃 我有在努力存钱
Well, I have been trying to save my money.
很好 毕竟计划好未来是很重要的
Good for you. It's important to make plans for the future after all.
请进
Feel free to just head on in.
往前直走就是仓库
The warehouse is just straight ahead.
谢谢！
Thanks so much!
我的天 这个可真重
Oh man, this is heavy.
喂 你能不能小心一点？这个东西可是很贵重的！
Hey! Could you please be more careful? That thing's, like, vintage!
哎哟 对不住
Oops. My bad.
别担心 冠军 这就是一件破烂
No worries, champ. It's a piece of junk.
你疯了吗？你根本不知道—
Are you insane? Do you have any idea how much that --
我懂的 先生
I totes got it, sir.
我扔掉自己的第一部手机的时候心里也很难受
You know, I had a hard time throwing away my first cell phone.
有时 赋予价值的是我们的感情
Sometimes sentimental value is worth the most.
你完全没有明白！
You don't get it at all!
井出 求你了
Ah come on, Ide.
我们去游乐场吧？
Can we please go?
我对游乐园一点都没有兴趣
I'm not interested in amusement parks.
你为什么不找马可？
Why don't you ask Marco to go or something?
那家伙今天都没有来上学
That jackal didn't even come to school today.
他好像是有工作
I think he had to work.
他不上学去打工？
He prioritized a part-time job over school?
就你还有脸说他？兄弟 别这样
You're one to talk. Be a sport, dude.
如果我们找一个女生一起 就只用付原票价的1%
If we take a girl, they'll give you a 99% discount.
而我可以邀请爱子 好不好？
And I can invite Aiko. So, pleeeease?
其实不是我邀请爱子的
Well, I didn't technically invite Aiko.
想去的人是她
She was the one who wanted to go.
她这么说来着 「我想跟你一起去游乐园
Saying stuff like, "I want to go to the amusement park with you.
但是我说不出口因为我好害羞」
I didn't want to ask 'cause it's so embarrassing."
喂 井出
Hey. Ide.
你在听我说话吗？
You listening to me?
诸位 听我说
So, listen up, everybody
我有一个重要的事情要宣布
‘cause I have an important announcement to make.
我要…我要结婚了！
'Kay? Uh, I am... gonna get married!
因此我决定辞职了
And that's why I've decided to quit being a teacher.
今天是我最后一天担任教职
Today is my last day.
从今往后 我就是一个主妇了
I'm gonna be a housewife from now on.
作为告别 我要给你们讲一个故事
Since this is goodbye, let me tell you a story --
关于我和丈夫如何相爱的
how my husband and I fell in love.
所以我和老公是在大豆游乐场相遇的
So, my hubby and I met at the Ozu amusement park.
正是夕阳西下
I was there during sunset.
笨拙的我即将被过山车碾压
Clumsy ol' me was about to get run over by a roller coaster,
说时迟那时快 有个人救了我
when all of a sudden, someone saved me.
他就是我老公！
It was my hubby!
记住 年轻人 游乐园就是天堂！
Remember, young ones, amusement parks are a paradise!
年轻人 丢下书本
Young people, toss your text books.
去游乐园吧！
Let's go to the parks!
走！走！走！走起！
Go! Go! Go! Goooooo!!
云雀弄…
Hibaji...
你怎么了喵？好像心情不好
What's the matter, nya? You look kinda down.
女孩的烦恼喵？
Girl problems, nya?
我真正希望去游乐园的人是你
You know, you're the one that I really wanted to go to the amusement park.
我不会去的
I'm not going.
云雀弄！
Hibaji!
请不要纠缠她 晴子老师
Please stop bothering her, Ms. Haruko.
我们俩需要谈一谈
You and I need to talk.
云雀弄 你留在这里
Hibajiri, you stay here.
嗯？
Hm?
请你不要把酷美卷入你的计划里
I don't want to you involved Hidomi in your schemes.
瞧瞧你 好一位骑士
Wow, look at you. Quite the white knight, pyon.
『I think I can』—　The Pillows
好吧 打就打
Okay. Let's do this.
你真的没有才能喵
You really got no talent, nya.
没用的
Nope.
还是没用
And another nope.
你应该学学怎么用自己的球棒战斗
You gotta learn how to fight with your own bat.
不管你要做什么 都要用力去做！
Whatever you want to do, you have to do it with strength!
转动腰胯 手臂放松 下巴收紧
Use your hips. Arms relaxed. Keep your chin tucked in.
收紧
Tuck it in.
不行！你完全不行！
No good! You're no good at all!
你完全没有成长
I don't see you growing.
可惜 真可惜
What a shame. What a real shame.
离酷美远一点！
Just stay away from Hidomi!
如果人的强大是由他能承受的伤害决定
If strength was measured by the hits one could take,
那么你就没有那么失败了
then you wouldn't be considered such a loser.
实话说 我对你有过期待
To be honest, I thought you'd be better.
这就是我用了那么多时间教育你的原因
That's why I invested all that time teaching you those things.
但是看来只是白费力气
But I guess it was for nothing,
因为你什么也不懂
'cause you know nothing.
晴子老师 我也很失望
I'm disappointed, too, Ms. Haruko.
你也什么也不懂
You also know nothing.
事实上 你满足不了我
The truth is, you don't satisfy me.
怎么回—
What's going o--
呃 我的错？
Uh, my bad.
最近事情好像会变得比往常更糟
Things might get worse than usual this time around.
我等着
I'll be waiting.
FLCL Progressive
情侣价只有原价的1%
99% off admission for all couples!
好便宜！
What a deal!
爱子你在哪？！
Where are you, Aiko?!
欢迎
大豆游乐园
你不明白我的心情
You don't understand how I feel.
渡 你为什么总是这样？
Why are you always like this, Wataru?
美咲… - 为什么！
Misaki... Come on!
…我喜欢你
...I love you.
我也喜欢你！
I love you, too!
裕也？
Yuya?
我… 我想…
I, uh... I would like...
我想和你一起坐旋转茶杯！
I would like to ride the teacups with you!
裕也 你能不能不要总是出现在附近？
Yuya! Why do you keep showing up randomly?
渡 我…终于明白了自己的感情
Wataru... I... I finally realized my true feelings.
我不想知道 已经太迟了！
I don't want to hear it. You're too late.
-裕也！ -渡！
Yuya! Wataru!
不要为了我这种人争吵 求你们了！
Please stop fighting over little old me!
■
N.O. 总量
测试运行还有多久？
Um, how much longer is this test ride?
很快就会结束了
Oh, not too much longer.
你只要乖乖待在那里就行了
All you have to do is stay right there, okay?
■
仅限一天
青春情侣日
海盗船袭来
和渡渡鸟君聊天吧
等一下 不是这个
Wait. Hold on. Not that one.
什么？我以为是渡渡鸟君
What? I thought it was Mr. Dodo.
别忘了 这是超高级别的机密
Don't forget, we're dealing with ultra-top-secret stuff here,
所以我们要进入机密通话模式
so we got to go into the secret-communication mode.
在购物页面点击几维鸟挂坠
Push little kiwi strap at the shopping section.
哈？哪一个？
Huh? Which one is that one?
底部中间那个毛茸茸的
The fluffy one at the bottom in the middle.
你确定吗？打开的是个菜单
Are you sure? The link went to a menu.
接下来点「她很鸡翅套餐」
You have to push She's So Chicky Wings next.
「伊卡路斯跳楼机是世界第三快的跳楼机」？
"The Icarus Fall is the world's third-fastest falling ride"?
等 等 等一下 就是那个 往回翻
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on. Right there. Go back.
-哈？-就是那个！
Huh? That one!
就是那个 正在下落的那个
The uh... the uh... You know, the falling one.
这些好像都在下落
Uh... They're all, like, falling.
那个小鸸鹋样子的
The one with the little emu
哪一个？
But which one?
翅膀毛茸茸的那个
The one with the fluffy wings.
具体一点！
Be more specific.
这里！
There!
你们好！我是渡渡鸟君！
Hello there! It's Mr. Dodo!
是我
It's me.
不要摆出那副的表情 有时小孩子会误打误撞点进来
Don't act sorry. Sometimes a kid'll call in by mistake.
-你好 渡渡鸟君！你好 小朋友！
-Hi, Mr. Dodo! -Hey, kid!
我看到海盗船已经装好了
I saw the Viking ship was installed.
但是还有入境方面的事情要打理
Also, we still need to deal with the Immigration matters.
我希望你不要心急
But I don't want you to have to rush.
花盆呢? 已经完成了吗？
What about the flower plant?  Is it complete?
当然 随时可以启动
Sure. Uh, it can be activated any time.
真的？
Really?
已经搞定了
The plant is up, okay?
你现在还有没有什么情报告诉我们？
Now what intel do you have for us?
你们好！我是渡渡鸟君！
Uh, hello there!   It's Mr. Dodo!
别过来！
Ew! Get away!
你能不能专注于你真正的工作？
Can you focus on your real job?
我把数据发过去了
I sent the data.
这也是真正的工作
This is a real job, too.
你不知道利润是用来资助—
Don't you know that this part helps fund --
没有花盆能行吗？
Do you think you can do it without the flower pot?
估计不行
Doubt it.
如果不能启动花盆
If you can't activate the flower pot,
任何计划都是白费力气
any plan you come up with will be useless.
闭嘴 我明白
Shut up. I know that.
爱子
Aiko.
怎么了？
What is it?
我好渴…
I'm so thirsty...
水 水…
W-water...
『Fool on the Planet』—　The Pillows
我不想回忆起今早发生的事情
I don't want to remember what happened this morning.
啊啦 快看 酷美酱！
Oh, my. Hidomi, look.
这一定是仁由小姐呢
It must be Jinyu's doing.
打碎了那么多盘子 心里非常在意吧
She must've felt bad about breaking so many plates.
也许吧
I guess so.
酷美酱 你变了呢
Hidomi, dear. You've changed.
我只是变回原来的自己而已
I'm back to my usual self is all.
不 不是这样的 你真的变了
No, you're different. Completely different.
…我 变了…？
I've...changed...?
原来如此
I see...
你…你在干什么？
What... what are you doing?
路上小心 酷美酱
Have fun at school, Hidomi.
井出君 是你的朋友吧 他挺可爱的呢
By the way, your friend Ide? He's very cute.
为什么…
Why are you...?
酷美酱的事情我全都知道
I know everything about you, Hidomi.
妈妈我可是酷美酱的妈妈呀
I am your mommy after all.
不是这个… -喜欢他吗？
That's not what I... Do you like him?
我说的不是这个！
That's not what I'm talking about!
要关掉吗？咖啡店…
You're closing it down? The cafe? Why?
为什么？！为什么要这样？！
Why would you do that?
难道不是要在这里等父亲回来的吗？！
I thought you were going to stay here and wait till Dad comes home!
我觉得也差不多了…
I think it's time to stop.
你们好！我是渡渡鸟君！
Hi! I'm Mr. Dodo!
看起来每个人都玩得很开心 对吧？
Looks like everyone is having a real good time. Am I right?
男孩们和女孩们！
Hey! Boys and girls!
你们这些下面毛都没长全的小屁孩！
You're little brats who still don't have all your hair down there!
很抱歉 但是你们都一无是处！
Sorry, but you are all pretty much useless!
开火！
Fire!
等一下 声音错了
Hold on. Wrong voice.
开火！
Fire!
他们已经开始了吗？
They started already?
『Last Dinosaur』—　The Pillows
等等 不
Ahh! Wait! No!
队长！情况不妙
Captain! It doesn't look like we'll make it.
我们必须这么做
We've got to do it.
无论如何 我们向他们宣告
No matter what. We'll show them.
就算我们的褶皱被熨平
Even if our wrinkles get flattened,
我们也要战斗到最后一刻
we are going to fight to the very end!
开始攻击！
Start the attack!
■
入国管理局　遗失物保管用卫星仓库
哎呀 这是谁呀？
Oh, my. What do we have here?
多么可爱的客人
What an adorable guest you are.
饿了吗？
You're hungry, aren't you?
可怜的小家伙
Oh, you poor thing.
欸？他们在做了吗
Huh? So, they're doin' it, huh?
云雀弄 你看起来不错
Lookin' good, Hibaji.
你干得非常好
You're killin' it!
别急 别急呀
Wah-ho! Hold on. Hold on.
别这样 我可什么都没干
Oh, come on. Stop it. I did nothing wrong.
我只是在你们这些年轻人背上轻轻推了一把
All I did was give you youngsters a little nudge,
为了帮助你们实现梦想 你知道的
to help your dreams along. You know that.
把他还给我！把井出还给我！
Give him back! Give Ide back to me!
这就是中学生的真正力量吗？
Wah-ho! So this is the real strength of a middle-school student, huh?
到头来 你跟其他人没有区别
In the end, you're no different than the rest of them.
这都是因为你喜欢那只怪鸟 对不对？
It's all because you like that weird bird, am I right?
蠢透了 你不过是一个陷入爱情的女孩
How stupid. You're just a girl in love!
是 Atomsk
It's Atomsk.